brctv.com 2010-09-01

# Customer Notifications : Blue Ridge Communications

|  |  |   
---|---|---  
| 

  * **You Are Here:**
  * Home
  * > Customer Notifications

---  
  
### Blue Ridge Web Page Privacy Statement

|   
| 

Blue Ridge Cable Technologies, Inc., d/b/a Blue Ridge Communications. is the organization that produces the Blue Ridge Website (Website). We are committed to safeguarding your privacy online. This Privacy Policy is applicable to this Website.

**General**  
You may visit our website without disclosing any personal information. We may, however, offer some services or specifically request personal information. The personal information we collect may include, but is not limited to, first and last name, street address, e-mail address, telephone number (e.g., home, work, mobile and/or fax), and birthdate. We may also collect other personal information that will be identified on the applicable page(s) of the Website. If you submit any personal information to us, or to our third party service providers acting on our behalf, you can be assured that we will not sell, lease, or share your personal information with or to anyone else, except as follows: (1) to our third party service providers, and only so that they may help us provide the services you've requested and in certain circumstances to provide you with ticket or merchandise related offers; and (2) on occasion, we may offer a special promotion (such as a sweepstakes or other contests on the Website or otherwise or in conjunction with a third party service provider, sponsor or promotional partner, and share your information with that sponsor or promotional partner so that it can send you other special promotions it offers, but only if you give us permission to do so. 

**Special Offers and Promotions.**

With your permission, we may also send you e-mails with special offers and promotions. If you don't want to receive these, you may unsubscribe to our newsletter. 

**Automatically Collected Information.**  
We may use automatic methods such as cookies (small amounts of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a Website's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive) to understand Website trends, deliver a more personalized experience and to improve our content and offerings. Examples of the information we may collect and analyze using these methods include, the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; e-mail address; type and version, operating system, and platform; purchase history, which we may aggregate with similar information from other customers; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, on, and from our Website, including date and time; and cookie information. We may also use software tools to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows the user to accept or reject cookies. If you set your browser not to accept cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of certain services on our Website.

We do not transfer cookies associated with our Website to any unrelated company, nor do we authorize any other companies to access the cookies we have placed on your computer's hard drive. We may allow other companies that are presenting advertisements or providing services on our pages to set and access cookies on your computer. Those companies' use of cookies will be covered by their own privacy policies, not ours.

We do not install any spyware or adware in connection with our Website, or distribute any commercial message, or authorize any third party to distribute any commercial message, by means of spyware or adware. "Spyware" or "adware" is any software which has been downloaded to and/or installed on an Internet user's computer, without the user's actual consent, and facilitates the distribution of any commercial message to the user. If you feel you may have spyware from another company installed on your machine, there are various anti-spyware/adware software applications available on the Internet to identify if this has occurred.

**Aggregated Demographic Information.**  
We may share aggregated demographic information with third parties, but this information is not linked to any personal information that can identify you or another individual person. Therefore, no personal information is disclosed in this manner. Business Transfers. In the future, Penn's Peak may be sold along with its assets, or other transactions may occur in which customer information is one of the business assets transferred. In such a case, the customer information which we have gathered may be one of the business assets we transfer. Disclosure for Legal Purposes. The law requires that we may be required to share your personal information and non-personal information (see "Cookies" section above for examples of non-personal information) pursuant to judicial or governmental subpoenas, warrants or orders. If we are required to do so, we will, of course, obey the law. In addition, notwithstanding any term to the contrary in this Privacy Policy, we reserve the right to use and disclose share your personal and non-personal information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of this Website's Terms of Use, or as otherwise required by law. 

**Links**  
Our Website contains links to other sites websites operated by unrelated third parties. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third party websites. We encourage you to be aware of this when your leave our Website and to read the privacy policies of every website that collects personally identifiable information from you. The Privacy Policy applies only to this Website. 

**Contact Us**  
If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at: Blue Ridge Communications, PO Box 215, 613 Third Street, Palmerton, PA 18071 or [brc@ptd.net](mailto:brc@ptd.net?subject=Privacy%20Policy). 

Notification of Changes  
Any changes to this policy will be listed on this page. 

**LAST UPDATED AND EFFECTIVE DATE: March 8, 2005.**  
---  
  
### Customer Notifications

|   
  
**Notifications for Blue Ridge Communications**  
As required by law, we are notifying our customers of their right to privacy, our complaint procedure, billing procedure, refund policy, converter/ TV compatibility and subscriber service procedure. 

**Privacy Notice**  
The notice is being provided in accordance with the Cable Television Consumer Protection and Competition Act of 1992, a Federal law which requires all cable operators to notify subscribers of the collection, use and disclosure of personally identifiable information regarding cable subscribers.

Blue Ridge Communications collects and maintains certain information, concerning individual subscribers, which is necessary to provide cable television service to our subscribers and to detect unauthorized reception of our service. Such information includes billing records, service maintenance and repair records, premium service subscription, marketing and research survey information and subscriber complaints.

We do not maintain this information any longer than is necessary for our business purposes. Information such as credit references, previous address, social security and driver license numbers are maintained, for purpose of identity regarding the applicants for our services, for a period of five (5) years. After such time, if the purpose for which such information was collected has been accomplished, Blue Ridge Communications will destroy the information.

As a subscriber, you may review (and correct if necessary) any personal information held by us that pertains to you. These records are available at the local Blue Ridge Communications office, serving you, during the hours of 9 AM to 5 PM, Monday through Friday.

We request that you contact us beforehand by telephone or letter so that we may locate the information and set up an appointment for your review.

Blue Ridge Communications may from time-to-time make your personal information available to our sales agents, research consultants, our accountants, programming services, representatives of franchising authorities, and collection agencies for the purpose of collecting money owed by a subscriber. Names and addresses of Blue Ridge Communications subscribers are provided to Program Guide distributors for the purpose of mailing; please notify our office by telephone or letter if you do not want to be included on the list.

Any person, who feels aggrieved by an action of Blue Ridge Communications in violation of Section 631 of the Cable Television Consumer Protection and Competition Act of 1992, may bring a civil action in a United States District Court. The Cable Act restricts the collection of subscriber information and the disclosure of personally identifiable information.

If Blue Ridge Communications is served with a court order requiring disclosure of personally identifiable information concerning a subscriber, we will inform the subscriber before any such information is released. Under some circumstances, a governmental entity may seek a court order to obtain personally identifiable subscriber information from a cable system concerning one of its subscribers. The subscriber would then be given an opportunity to contest issuance of such an order.

In emergency situations, 911 Response Centers may contact us for directions to a subscriber's home. We will release this information unless you contact us in advance. 

**Complaint Procedure**  
Subscribers may call their local service office to register complaints about the quality of the television signals they receive. 

Complaints to the local office will be recorded, with the time received, the nature of the complaint along with the name, address and phone number of the subscriber calling in. 

In most cases, any complaints about technical quality of signals will be investigated within 48 hours of receipt, with a visit to your premises by a field technician. If a service call is not required, you will be informed as to the correction of the complaint immediately. 

If the local service office is unable to resolve the problem, you may direct correspondence to: 

Ephrata, Duncannon, Newberry Areas:  
Tom Acker  
P.O. Box 150, Ephrata, PA 17522  
or call 717-733-4111

All Other Areas:  
Jeff Crandall  
P.O. Box 215, Palmerton, PA 18071  
or call 610-826-2551

We are committed to resolving your complaints promptly. If you feel the complaint was not handled or resolved properly, you may wish to register a complaint with the local franchising authority. Calls may be directed to the Secretary of the Borough or Township in which you reside.

**Billing Procedure**

  1. Statements are issued in the beginning of the billing period. We offer Annual, Semi-Annual, Quarterly and Monthly billing. Payment is due on the date stated on the statement, for the total amount.
  2. If you do not pay your bill on or before the due date, you will be asked to pay an additional $3 per month for the service (late adjustment).
  3. Your first bill will reflect charges from the date of installation.
  4. Installation fees will be billed.
  5. If you receive a delinquent notice, the balance is required to be paid in full.
  6. A fee of $20 will be charged for returned checks.
  7. All disconnected accounts are required to return converters and remotes to a Blue Ridge Communications office. Disconnected accounts will be charged if they do not return their converter(s) and remote(s). However, credit will be given upon reconnection or return of converter(s) and remote(s).

**Telephone Monitoring**  
From time-to-time we will be monitoring/or recording customer phone calls in order to ensure quality customer service. 

**Internet Privacy**  
For Blue Ridge High Speed Internet customers, personally identifiable information is collected in the course of furnishing Internet access. We adhere to the provisions of the PenTeleData Acceptable use policy, which is found at <http://www.ptd.net/POLICIES-RES.html>. We comply with the Electronic Communications Privacy Act and all copyright laws including the Digital Millennium Copyright Act. In case of an emergency, we will provide personally identifiable subscriber information to authorized requestors upon receipt of a subpoena, search warrant, or court order without first notifying the subscriber. We do not retain personally identifiable information related to Internet access longer than is necessary for business purposes. We will periodically email you information from Blue Ridge and Blue Ridge marketing partners. To unsubscribe, follow the instructions in the email. 

**Service Procedure**  
The following Service Procedure adopted by Blue Ridge Communications is in compliance with the FCC standards.  

  1. Standard installations will be performed within seven business days after an order has been placed. (“Standard means any installation located within 125 feet of existing distribution system.”)
  2. Excluding any conditions beyond the control of the operator, work on “Service Interruptions” will begin within 24 hours after the interruption becomes evident.
  3. Installations and other installation related activities will be scheduled within a four hour time period during normal business hours. If the installer is running late and will be unable to keep the appointment, it shall be rescheduled at the convenience of the customer.
  4. Service is provided consistent with 47USC 76.309.

**Refund Policy**  
When you terminate cable service with us, depending on what day of the month you terminate, you may receive a credit for those days of service which you prepaid and did not use the service.   
If the amount of the refund is $1.99 or less, it is our policy not to refund this amount to you due to the cost of processing. Amounts of $2.00 or greater will be automatically sent to you at the last address indicated on your bill. If you want the check sent to a new address, you must notify your local office. 

**Consumer Education**  
Some older TV sets and VCRs do not have enough channel capacity to provide all of the channels we make available. A converter may be necessary to view these channels. The converter does not need to have descrambling capabilities. When using any cable converter you may not be able to benefit from some of the special functions of your TV set and VCR. For example: to view one channel while recording another; to watch and record two different TV shows at the same time; to use advanced picture generation and display features such as “picture in picture.” Converters are available from local retailers or directly from Blue Ridge Communications.  
If Blue Ridge Communications has provided you with a remote control for use with a converter or other device, please be advised that compatible remote controls are available from retail outlets. Many remotes designated as “universal remotes” will operate the converter boxes. You may contact your local Blue Ridge Communications office for advice prior to purchasing a remote control. Digital customers: Instructions for parental controls are located at[ http://www.brctv. com/customer_care/troubleshooting/pdf/using_parental_control.pdf](http://www.brctv.com/customer_care/troubleshooting/pdf/using_parental_control.pdf) and in your welcome packet. Analog customers can find parental control instructions in the remote control manual. 

**BLUE RIDGE DIGITAL PHONE COMPANY**  
Digital Phone service is provided through Blue Ridge Digital Phone Company. Subscriber rights and obligations are found in the tariff on file with the Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission and at: [http://www.brctv.com/prodserv/digital_phone/index.php](http://www.brctv.com/prodserv/digital_phone/index.php.). 

**Main Office** : P.O. Box 215, 613 Third Street  
Palmerton, PA 18071  
Phone: (610) 826-2551

Branch Offices:  
**Duncannon Office**  
1 Water Street Duncannon, PA 17020   
Phone: (717) 834-5715   
**Hours Sat** : 8am-noon

**Ephrata Office**  
Ephrata Office P.O. Box 150 804 Academy Heights Ave. Ephrata, PA 17522   
Phone:(717) 733-4111   
**Hours Sat** : 8am-noon

**Gilbert Office**  
P.O. Box 100 Route 209 & Ye Olde Professional Building Gilbert, PA 18331   
Phone:(610) 681-6100   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Hawley Office**  
2569 Route 6 Hawley, PA 18428   
Phone:(570) 226-4914   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Lansford Office**  
Lansford Office 20 W. Ridge St. Lansford, PA 18232  
Phone:(570) 645-5511   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Lehighton Office**  
200 North First St. Lehighton, PA 18235  
Phone:(610) 377-2250   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Mansfield Office**  
46 North Academy St. Mansfield, PA 16933  
Phone:(570) 662-2369   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Milford Office**  
112 Bennett Ave. Milford, PA 18337  
Phone:(570) 296-8200   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Newberry/York Haven Office**  
2800 Lewisberry Rd. York Haven, PA 17370   
Phone:(717) 938-6501   
**Hours Sat** : 8am-noon

**Pencor Super Store**  
656 Delaware Avenue Palmerton, PA 18071   
Phone:(610) 826-9311   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Pocono Summit Office**  
115A Route 940 Pocono Summit, PA 18346   
Phone:(570) 839-3550   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Stroudsburg Office**  
920 Ehler St. Stroudsburg, PA 18360   
Phone:(570) 421-0780   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Tunkhannock Office**  
P.O. Box 141 Route 29 & Dymond Terrace Tunkhannock, PA 18657   
Phone:(570) 836-5422   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Walnutport Office**  
239 Lehigh Gap Street Walnutport, PA 18088   
Phone:(610) 767-6383   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm

**Wellsboro Office**  
15 Crafton St. Wellsboro, PA 16901   
Phone:(570) 724-4516   
**Hours Sat** : 9am-1pm  

|  |   
---
